NahamSec is a name that needs no introduction.
He's both a top hacker and a top content creator
in the bug bounty space.
And this gives him a unique perspective because
based on your comments, based on the questions
you as the audience ask, NahamSec sees what
you are getting wrong.
And if you want to know what this is, then
enjoy the episode.
Hello Ben.
Thank you so much for joining me for the podcast
today.
To more people, you are known as NahamSec
and please tell us about your background and
how did you get to the point that you are
currently at?
Start wherever you want to start.
Yeah.
Hi, I'm Ben.
Most people online, as you mentioned, know
me as NahamSec.
I've been hacking for, or professionally I've
been hacking for about, I want to say 10 years.
I got into bug bounties in late 2013 or early
2014 and I just heard people are getting money
from hacking companies and I was like, oh,
I can probably do this.
Back then there was only a couple of companies
hacking, it was like Yahoo, Facebook, Google,
I think Coinbase launched like years later,
a year or two later.
Yeah, I just wanted, I was a college kid,
I wanted to figure out what I want to do.
I didn't like my degree really.
I didn't want to become a developer, so I
always loved hacking and I did it as pranks
from my friends and when I was a kid I pranked
my friends doing hacking or hacking with Sub7
and things like that when that was around
back then.
And yeah, I got into bug bounties and then
later I met some folks at Bug Crowd, I met
some people at HackerOne.
I ended up getting employed at HackerOne and
I think getting employed at HackerOne kind
of pushed me to do better and I really wanted
to build a community for hackers and having
the access that I did with HackerOne, it made
it easier for me to make the community happen
and meet everybody and collaborate with everybody.
So yeah, I want to say I'm a product of bug
bounties and I've had a career because of
bug bounties.
Are you now doing bug bounty full time?
Full time-ish.
I don't know if I would say I'm doing it full
time, full time, but it's one of my primary
sources of income.
I think I've gone to a point where I could
do part time bug bounty and still make a good
living out of it, but I have multiple jobs.
I did my pen test, I did bug bounties, I create
content, I offer trainings, I do public speaking,
I have a couple of other side hustles, but
bug bounties is still the thing that I enjoy
doing the most and it's given me a lot of
opportunities.
I still participate very regularly, but I
wouldn't say I'm spending 40, 50 hours a week
like I used to back in the day.
Yeah, of course.
It was the question I knew you will answer
more or less this because I'm also a bit annoyed
when people ask me if I'm a full time bug
bounty hunter, like thinking that all the
time spent creating content and everything,
and you do even more things than I do.
So obviously, you can't be a full time bug
bounty hunter, but you don't work, you are
not employed anywhere else, is what I meant.
I work for myself now, yeah.
I started working for myself back in November,
so a lot of people that know me mostly is
from HackerOne, but I left HackerOne a year
and a half ago.
I joined another startup, another Dutch startup
for the attack surface management stuff, and
then in November, things didn't work out and
I've been loving doing the content thing for
a while and I think it was just the right
time to just push myself to do this full time
and it's given me the opportunity to do more
stuff for myself, more stuff for the community,
go back to hacking and just have a little
bit more freedom of what I want to do versus
having to juggle a full time job and then
everything else that I was doing already.
But yeah, I think the thing that a lot of
hackers don't understand is I think the first
couple of years is when you do full time hacking,
where it's considered like you work the, I
don't want to say I did nine to five, but
you're putting a good eight, nine, ten hours
a day because not only you're learning, but
you want to hack to learn, right?
You're learning and then you're doing hands-on
thing with bug bounties and as more and more
you do those things, it becomes more natural.
Some steps are automated in the past couple
of years or some things you understand better
and you grasp the idea quicker or you know
if they're vulnerable and things like that.
So it just becomes, I think the more experience
you gain, the less time you spend.
But I mean, I know hackers that are spending
enormous amount of times and making hundreds
of thousands a month.
Yeah, we'll definitely come back to this in
a second.
But tell me what did you do at HackerOne?
So I joined HackerOne as an intern and before
I left, I was the head of hacker education
for HackerOne.
I worked from anywhere in the beginning from
working off with our sales team to help bring
in customers, educate customers.
I was the first person to do triage at HackerOne.
I think outside of the co-founders, I was
the first one that was hired on the triage
team.
I helped build the triage team a little bit
or be a part of it.
And then I worked on the customer service
team.
And then eventually I realized like I like
to go to conferences and I like educating
people and I asked my boss, Luke Tucker was
my boss at the time that I wanted to do it.
He actually offered me to do education and
it was kind of a hard thing to shift over
to because it's no longer as technical as
it sounds because you're doing community work.
But it was something that I really enjoyed
and it was more of a creating CTFs to teach
people or creating content to teach people
or outsourcing content to be created for Hacker101.
So everything you see on Hacker101, it was
done by me and somebody else, Dakin, who was
in charge of Hacker101 before they left.
And then I took over and like most of the
CTFs that were newer were designed by me and
then created by Adam Langley, who was the
CTF person that coded the CTF versus the stuff
that I designed like the scenario and so on.
Okay.
And so now of all the activities you do, you
just mentioned bug bounty, pen tests, courses,
creating content.
And I don't think if I missed anything, what
are the activities you enjoy the most?
I still love the public speaking aspect of
it.
I still love going to conferences and speaking.
It gives me the chance to like travel to go
to different places and talk to different
backgrounds and different people.
And I also still enjoy the bug bounty and
obviously content creation is probably one
of the most enjoyable things.
I think bug bounties is what I do to get that
like itch of wanting to like do something
technical like being behind a keyboard, something
with a pen test.
With a pen test, I don't have the freedom
to do whatever I want.
Pen test is like pen testing an app and getting
it done.
And then with content, I get the creativity
out.
I get to get creative and produce some art,
right?
Like I get to create the thumbnails.
I get to think about the story I want to tell.
I get to talk about like the things that I
want to talk about and they're very inspirational
more than anything.
But that gives me the art that I want to do
because I think that's some form of art.
You're creating something.
It's a form of art.
So I enjoy honestly a lot of the things that
I do.
I can't say what is the one thing that I enjoy
the most to be honest.
I enjoy them all.
Yeah, but you actually mentioned I think most
of them which just speaks to people that you
are in the right place because you enjoy most
if not all the things you do.
So that sounds really great.
Yeah, I mean there are times where I wake
up and I don't want to do anything.
I have those days when I wake up and I don't
want to make videos.
This week has been really hard to record videos
because I just came back from travel last
week and I'm still getting back into my routine
and I have a bunch of stuff that I have to
catch up on.
So I've been pushing video recording all week
and today I have to sit down and record Monday's
video and make sure I have it ready to be
out by Monday.
I have those days like everybody else but
it's just mostly I've learned how to like
push myself and also telling myself like,
yeah, if I don't want to make a video today,
I'll do something else that I have to do on
my to-do list and then get to it later.
Yeah, yeah, I definitely know what you mean.
I struggle a lot with coming back to the work
mode after some traveling, after some trips.
It always takes me so much time and back in
the days when I would work nine to five, I
would just be at work because I had to so
I didn't have this problem.
And it's different because like when you work
a nine to five, even if you don't perform
at your best, you still have a guaranteed
paycheck.
It's okay when you're...
I'm not saying it's okay like after work but
when you come back, I think people are more
understanding for the first couple of days
until you get back in the routine.
It's normal.
But when you work for yourself, I feel like
it's a little bit of different pressure.
Yeah, and probably if you work a little bit
less productively for the three days after
the trip, no one just will not notice because
no one's monitoring close enough.
Absolutely, yeah.
So being in the back bounty pretty much since
the beginning because I think I can safely
say this and working at HackerOne, how did
you see the industry change over the years?
It's very cool to see almost like every company
now has a bug bounty program or a VDP at least.
I see often more companies where I type in
the name and the word security where something
pops up than I used to 10 years ago.
And then the amount of people that are doing
bug bounties now, it's insane.
The amount of people that have done bug bounties
or have something for bug bounties, either
they're content creators because of bug bounties
or because they're pen testers because they
learned about HackerOne or something, or just
even the people that are freelancing bug bounties
and it's insane.
The leaderboard is like, you just look at
it now.
I used to know almost everybody on the leaderboard
back in the day.
But now I look at it and I go, I don't even
know who these people are.
Like there's so many people now, it's hard
to know everybody.
I think that has been a good shift and I think
the bug bounty community has helped create
a lot of the tools and the research that's
been done recently.
You look at somebody from an asset note from
Chopin and Shaw and his team at Asset Note,
they're crushing research and I'm not saying
they're doing it because of bug bounties,
but they all come from a bug bounty background
and they use bug bounties as a proving ground.
They find a vulnerability, they see how many
bug bounty programs can they exploit.
And then when they finish that, you see all
these other bug bounty hunters using things
like Nukely, who was also created by bug bounty
hunters to go after the targets that they
may have not had access to.
I think it's just bug bounties have contributed
to a good large scale of the security posture
of organizations, whether it's to have a bug
bounty program or they're using tools that
were created by a bug bounty program or a
bug bounty hack hunter or just a knowledge
that was shared from a bug bounty hunter.
I think it's just the ecosystem of at least
web application security and ASM has been
drastically contributed to by bug bounty hunters
from HackerOne, BugCrowd or whatever other
platform you can think of.
Do you think it was easier a few years ago
because there were bugs everywhere or do you
think it is easier today because there are
so many resources?
I honestly think it's both.
It was easier because less knowledge was shared
back in the day, but the number of targets
were less.
It's like a double-edged sword, right?
It's like you have both sides of this thing.
Yeah, there was less programs, but less knowledge.
But now you have more knowledge, but more
programs.
And honestly, I still see the dumb easy cross-site
scriptings and IDORS and some of these large
organizations that are Fortune 500 or Fortune
100 or whatever you want to call them.
I still see the same mistakes happening over
and over and over.
So you can't say there are less bugs.
I just think there's more competition.
And honestly, it's disappointing a little
bit if you ask me because I think a lot of
these bug bounty hunters have the wrong idea
of automation and recon and everyone's focused
on the wrong things.
And that's what I'm finding vulnerabilities
and I think it gives the impression that there
are less bugs to be found.
But if there is less bugs to be found, how
are these companies paying millions of dollars
every month?
Yeah, and especially like life hacking events
show us that there are bugs everywhere.
But what wrong things do you mean here that
hunters focus on?
So I think a lot of the newer hunters think
like I have this super secret tool on my machine
that I launch a company name and it just goes
bugs, bugs, bugs, bugs.
It's not like that.
You know, you have things like nuclear that
does that.
I know people that have like slack integrations
and webhooks that does that.
Right.
But I want to say I don't want to give it
a percentage, but a large number of vulnerabilities
that come out that are good, that are paid
high enough.
It takes a lot of manual work.
They may have found something that's very
cool or very unique through recon, but the
exploitation is completely manual and takes
research.
You're finding out what this application is.
Is it open sourced?
Is there a similar data on this thing?
Is there a similar input that we can find
as a documentation?
Right.
And I think a lot of hackers don't want to
spend that time because let's be honest, it
looks boring.
It doesn't look fun.
It's a lot of hours to be spent.
But if you have the passion, it's a different
story.
I don't mind digging into the same program
for two weeks at a time until I find a bug
because 14 days and I spend and I make, I
don't know, let's say $20,000.
That's still more than a job.
I would have made in 18 days, right?
Yeah.
So the return is there.
It's just people want instant gratification.
I think it's a curse of the internet.
Everyone wants things quickly like this.
They want the bounty tomorrow.
I started today.
I must get a bounty tomorrow.
And that's not the case.
You don't, you know, there's only a few amount
of people that have the overnight success.
And unfortunately, it doesn't happen that
often in any industry.
Yeah.
It's even if we sometimes have these stories
that we find a bug very quickly, there are
for every bug like this.
There are a lot of the opposite stories where
you just spend a lot of time and didn't find
anything and you didn't publish anything.
Because what do you publish if you didn't
find a bug?
And it's hard for people to like understand
the full picture.
And the times, I'm sorry, just one more thing.
In times that you see like people are finding
bugs within a few hours, it's not because
it's not just because the application is vulnerable.
It's because these people have spent three,
four years knowing how quickly to spot something
that could be vulnerable to an IDOR or to
a SQL injection to an XSS.
The context of where these bugs happen is
becoming like a muscle memory to us, right?
Oh, I've seen this a million times.
When I see a webhook, instantly I go, I've
seen this a million times.
Is there an SSRI for an RCE in here?
But that comes with doing these so many times
to know I see X, I'm going to try Y, right?
Yeah.
That's 100% true.
So from one of your recent videos, I think
you kind of mentioned that you switch your
hacking style from being more recon oriented
to manual hacking.
Is this accurate?
It is.
I think I'm one of the people to blame about
this whole recon culture.
I did a lot of, you should do recon, recon
is this, recon is that.
I think it gave the wrong impression to a
lot of people.
So I need people to understand that you can
do recon, you can be successful at it, but
there are other ways to hack.
So I do recon, but nothing I do is automated.
I don't have a one line code that I go, it's
not like my lazy recon from back in the day.
That was like five years ago.
That worked five years ago.
Nuclear didn't exist five years ago.
People weren't doing things with nuclear and
sharing everything.
But yeah, I've switched to more of a go after
the core application, understand how the application
works, what vulnerabilities I can find, really
map out that company, how the asset works
with each other, instead of just going asset,
brute force, didn't find anything interesting.
Next asset, brute force, because that's what
most people do, I think.
It's like, I do recon, what do I do next?
Rip the application apart.
What does the application do?
How do you sign up?
How do you interact with other users?
And then going just fully doing that manually.
It's honestly more fun than doing recon, I
think.
Do you think it's a general trend?
Because in the last episode, Yassin said exactly
the same thing, that his hacking style changed
from being more recon oriented from having
automations into more just main app hacking.
I don't think it's a trend.
I think people bought into a hype and everyone
just like overly hyped this whole recon thing.
I think there is a room for doing recon.
There's room for reconnaissance.
You know, like a company like Apple, you need
to do reconnaissance to find applications
that are worth poking.
But there's a difference between doing reconnaissance
to find applications that are worth poking
at versus just getting lost in recon.
I know so many hackers like myself that just
enjoy doing recon more than anything else.
But you're not going to find vulnerabilities
with just looking for assets.
You know, I enjoy finding these random assets,
but what's next?
How are you going to do this, right?
And I think a lot of people are just scared
of the main applications because, oh, this
thing must be secure because it's a production
website that everybody's looking at, right?
So at the moment, how would you describe how
much time do you spend on recon versus how
much time do you spend on just manual hacking?
I just go as far as just running SubLister
at this point.
And then I will do some tooling on my SubLister
output to get titles because I want to know
titles and locations because I want to know
what these applications are.
So if it's a location that goes to an SSO,
I want to know.
If it's something that gets location for like
an Okta SSO, then it's a different story.
Like a user SSO and an Okta SSO are two different
things, internal versus like publicly facing
for users and partners.
And then I just look at applications that
look interesting, like, oh, OK, this thing
is going to a slash login.
Is it a slash sign up?
Is it a slash register?
Is there, how do I get an account?
How do I log into this thing?
And what's behind it for me to look at?
That's the main approach, I think.
OK, and now there's a very difficult question
because it's probably based heavily on your
experience.
But how do you decide which application is
interesting?
I think the context of the application is
very important.
So if I log in, so let's say I find a site,
something.site.com, what is the name of that
something?
Is it developer?
Is it dashboard, analytics?
The name usually gives you a hint.
And if that domain name doesn't give you a
hint, when you go into the application, they
tell you a purpose.
They go, if it's supposed to be a customer
facing site, it tells you like, sign up to
do X, Y, and Z.
So let's say like a bank.
It could tell you like, sign up to get your
credit score.
Oh, OK, credit score, I like that.
Is there a social security number in there
I could get?
Is there like addresses?
It's just assuming, what is this application
going to do?
What can I do with this application?
Or what this application is going to do for
me?
And then going into it and ripping it apart.
It just looks, it's from the looks.
You go look at it, or sometimes you see these
like, janky applications that are supposed
to be internal use only.
Huh, I wonder, can I register for this thing?
Is there a password I could do?
Like an admin password, admin password one.
So I can get in and hack on it.
There is all these different things.
Can I register with like a fake email maybe,
and it doesn't verify me to get in?
It's just the concept of just looking and
making assumptions of what this application
does, or what this application stores within
its site.
Yeah, and when you finally choose an application
to hack on, what are the first steps?
If I choose an application, it's first looking
at what the application looks like.
So it's more of a, so let's see what functionalities
has.
Is there multiple like user accesses, access
rules?
Because access rules give you a lot of fun
things to find for, right?
Like having a matrix of like, you know, when
you can select read, write, none.
If everything's on none for where a user,
can I read, can I write?
Can I do all these read, writes, all these
different access levels?
If I set this one to none, and then the rest
of them to all, that's a lot of vulnerabilities
to be found.
And all of those are different issues because
sometimes like three out of the 10 endpoints
are vulnerable to two other permissions.
Cool, that's six bugs that I found right there,
right?
The second thing is just looking at how it,
you know, validates user input.
So I like to find, people hate on this, but
the cost of scripting pays.
How does it access user?
You know, how does it take my user input?
Does it sanitize it?
If it does, how does it sanitize it?
Where does it go?
What areas of the page is my name going to
show up?
For example, even better, where can I assume
this username and my name's gonna show up
in their backend for a blind cross-site scripting,
right?
How do I trigger them to look for my account
for a black cross-site scripting?
How do I get my account, you know, flagged
for fraud?
So they go and look at my username or my email
or my name or my signature.
How do I cause some like investigation into
my account?
Wow, that's really thinking a few steps ahead.
The blind, so a lot of the early blind cross-site
scriptings that I used to get, I don't do
this anymore, was always making an order,
canceling it, ordering, canceling it, ordering,
canceling, ordering, canceling.
And then someone gets pissed off.
They go, who is this customer doing this?
Right?
And then when you make an order, that's one
flag.
And then it gets passed because it goes order,
shipping, you know, whatever.
There's like three steps to these things.
There's a warehouse.
And then sometimes it pops up in the warehouse
because I had it in my address.
It's like all these different things to go
through.
There's times when nothing fires.
I get a package with my cross-site scripting
payload in it.
Right?
Nothing happens, but it's just assuming all
these things.
I have no experience developing these applications,
but I've seen enough blind cross-site scriptings
fire to go, okay, I can make an assumption
what's happening.
I've seen enough internal assets to go, I
bet you to have this like fraud detection
thing.
Or I bet you if I put the wrong zip code for
my credit card a bunch of times, they're gonna
flag my account.
Okay.
And I also noticed here that it seems like
you have no problems with actually creating
an order, paying with the real money, and
sometimes even receiving the physical order.
I think my credit card company hates it because
of how many things I order on return.
I've tested the site that I was supposed to
for medication.
Somehow I can't get the cancer license.
They send me depression medication every month.
I don't take him.
I don't because I need it.
It's just, I was for a company that did like
mental health things, and I cancel it a bunch
of times.
And I'm like, maybe this will fire eventually.
My order is still there and I still get it
every month.
And then I go and like, you know, cancel eventually.
Yeah, I do.
It's not that, it's not really that hard to
order something.
You know, a lot of these companies have things
for $5.
I have the mattress company and the cheapest
item was like a book on their mattresses for
$15.
Okay, fine.
It's a $1,000 bounty right off like for an
hour of work.
I made an order.
Yeah, because even $1, I believe if someone
has to, a hunter has to use the real card,
it's like a big, big step for many.
And many just won't take this step and you
do.
And apparently you're happy with this.
Yeah, I mean, I have limits.
I will spend anywhere from a couple of dollars
to even like $100, $200 a month, like a subscription
if I have to.
Because I know if that $200 opens up functionality
that's not been tested by other bug bounty
hunters, the minimum payout is already, you
know, like $100.
I'm, you know, anything you find, any garbage
you find is going to be worth $100.
Yeah.
And I'm not going to report $100 bugs, but
you find two things that pays for it.
But if I find a medium level bug, that's $500.
One of them doubles my money already, right?
It's the investment that I'm doing.
It's just mostly gives you, um, gives you
things that you can double, triple, even like
10 times, 20 times your money.
Yeah, and I think there was a bug a few years
ago in Google where someone had to pay, but
it was real money.
It was like $1,000 or $2,000 for something.
And apart from giving the guy the bounty,
they also refunded him those thousands of
dollars that he paid.
So it was great.
There are some sketchy sites that I don't
recommend putting your credit card in.
I have another method for that.
My bank gives me like temporary cards.
There's some really sketchy sites that I wouldn't,
but most of those sketchy sites are usually
the ones to also refund me when I make a call.
Hey, here's my auto number.
Can you refund this for me, please?
Yeah.
So, um, we use Revolut a lot in Europe and
it has virtual cards with limits.
So, uh, so I'm also using these whenever I
have to do something like that.
Yeah.
So when you're analyzing the application,
what tools do you use?
Um, I pay for a burp suite.
Um, what is it called?
The not the community pain edition.
I have a professional, a professional, but
I only use like repeater and proxy.
I don't know why I want to switch to Kaido.
I hear really good stuff about Kaido.
I just haven't done it.
Um, I think that's about it.
Um, I do some tools to like reverse source
maps usually just to make it look nicer and
more pretty.
And my local box, I have JS parser that we
created years ago that I use.
I have J JS link finder.
I think is another one that I grew up and
created that I sometimes use.
Um, for application, nothing, honestly, I
have my own, you know, I have like a net cat
and burp collaborator.
I have my own cross-site scripting thing that
I put together with chat GPT.
And I think that's about it.
Most of this stuff is like on my web server.
I create like HTML or PHP files.
I do certain things that I needed to.
Uh, but I don't use a lot of more than all
of the tools anymore.
Not even Burp suite, um, like plugins.
Okay.
That's interesting.
I actually did have kind of a impression of
you of doing a lot of recon, using a lot of
tools and rely, relyinging a lot of tools.
And now I said, it's like the completely opposite.
No, I even like a lot of times I don't even
use Burp suite anymore.
I've really toned down on using tools.
Um, I had a few friends.
So I think, um, I don't know if it's a trend
or it was, I used to use scanners back in
the day to like scan for vulnerabilities,
vulnerabilities.
And then I would look at the vulnerability.
It would say SQL injection in this file.
And then I would go and look for the file
and see if I can exploit it myself.
When you use these tools, even if you're learning,
you get maybe just become reliant on them.
It just takes a fun out of it.
I'm very much like very, very, very, like
black or white.
Like it's, I'm either on this side or on that
side.
Either I use a lot of tools or I don't use
tools at all.
There's no, I can't find the right balance,
but I just feel like using a lot of tools
makes me just lazy and less productive.
And I rely on them too much.
So I've cut it down.
And, you know, even like with looking at a
webpage, I try to use the network tab more
than anything.
And then I switch over to Burp suite when
I want to like plus something in a repeater,
for example.
Yeah.
And actually they just added to Chrome the
ability to modify response headers in network
dev tools, which is also great.
I don't know if you need Burp anymore.
I mean, for me, at least at this point, but
it's just, I think you got to learn how to
do these things before you jump onto tools,
to be honest.
That's just me.
I just think there is a, I'm trying to make
sure the advice that I give people makes sense.
They, like I'm doing the things that I give
advice to.
So if I'm not living by the advice that I
give people, then why am I giving this advice
to them?
Right.
So if I tell you to stop doing recon, if I
don't stop doing it myself, then I'm a hypocrite.
Yeah.
And also like regarding automations and everything,
also often people ask me, how do you, what
should they automate?
My response is just automate something that
you are just tired of doing manually.
Your, I think your asset discovery stuff should
be automated.
For example, you should let a tool, for example,
look for like a sub-lister.
You should do that.
Your information gathering should be something
like sub-lister, but you don't need to automate.
I know people that are like sharing things
like, oh, do this one-liner to find cross-site
scriptings.
Why, why, why, or our SQL, why are we feeding
every endpoint to a SQL map?
What's the point in that, right?
That's an easy way to get banned with a WAF,
for example.
It's, I get that people want to be productive.
There's a difference between being productive
and just being straight up lazy.
Be productive, be efficient.
You should use the tools to make you faster,
not to make you money, if that makes sense.
Make you more efficient.
So the things that, like Nucleus is a good
example of it.
You can use, you can still make money by running
Nucleus templates and you can make some money,
but you can make more money if you have your
own Nucleus templates that you have found,
that you've eventually loaded into Nucleus.
I don't use Nucleus at all.
I don't like, it's not that I don't like Nucleus,
it's just, it just made me purely lazy doing
that kind of automation and there's so many
people that are doing Nucleus now.
You gotta stand out somehow.
Yeah, and so we are, we've talked a bit about
what people overrate, that they overrate recon
and using tools.
On the other hand, as a content creator, you
also give people a lot of tips and probably
sometimes you see that people don't appreciate
some tips as they should.
They don't ask correct questions.
What do you think are things that people don't
appreciate?
So one of the things that I made a comment
in one of my videos is a lot of people are
more worried about the what they use.
So if you look, anytime somebody posts something
on let's say on Twitter, I make a post that
says, I just had a cross-site scripting in
Google.
Do you know what the number one question is
that's gonna be responded to that tweet?
No idea.
What's the payload you used?
Of course, yeah.
Right?
Why is the question, what's the payload you
used and not how did you think of that?
Yeah, yeah.
Because the what doesn't fucking matter.
You can use a cross-site scripting payload.
It's not, you know, you can make your own
payload if you understand HTML and JavaScript.
I guess it's usually something easy or it's
some cool bypass that you could figure out
after a few steps of like, you know, fuzzing
the application, right?
But asking somebody like, why did you think
this cross-site scripting was gonna work?
Or why do you think the CSP bypass was gonna
work?
Right?
Or why did you think there's, why did you
think there's an RCE versus like how did you
exploit this RCE?
Yeah, that's a very good, very good tip.
People never ask this, never ask me this as
well.
Yeah, it's always what did you use?
What did you, what did you do?
Like what payload?
What's the payload?
I'm like, stop asking for the payload, dude.
Ask me how I thought about this.
You know, the payload doesn't matter.
It's my half, nine out of 10 times my payload
is a genetic cross-site scripting payload
or a genetic blind cross-site scripting payload.
But there is a closing tag before that everybody
else missed, right?
I skipped out of some tag that I knew was
gonna be there, but you're not asking me how
I knew this, right?
So this, I think the biggest thing is like,
if you're watching this, if you wanna become
a good bug bounty hunter, shifting the mentality
of like what tools they used and what payload
they used to how did they use that tool or
how did they think about this?
What is the thought process to get here is
more important.
That's one of the biggest ones.
And I know people who just copy paste payloads.
I copy paste my own payloads, but you don't
see me going like RCE payload and then like,
bam, bam, throwing them in every single, you
know, box that I see.
Yeah, and especially that, as you said, most
of payloads are just the, for me, most of
XSS were just the very basic payloads.
And the other times they are, they look complex
for someone, but they actually are very simple
if you follow the thought process, if you
see the filters that were there.
And also those that the complex payload often
makes absolutely no sense in any other target.
So copying and pasting, it just won't help
you in anything.
And actually understanding what happened,
this is what will give people bucks in other
applications.
And when I do my, you know, the live recon
streams that I do, I interview people.
One of the most common questions people ask
is like, can you ask him what tools this person
uses for subdomain enumeration?
I'm like, you understand, it doesn't really
probably matter.
Like all these tools, so you think about it,
like SubLister, Find Domain, I don't know,
X, Y, and Z, all these different ones, Amass,
Amass is kind of different, but let's just
put it in there for like the subdomain enumeration,
right?
They all have the same thing in common.
They hit the same APIs.
You have to give it the API key.
They all mostly hit the same sources and they
gave you similar data.
Some of them do better, some of them do more
because their searching queries are different,
right?
Everyone asks, what tool do you use?
But no one's asking, what do you do with this
data next?
Most people don't ask that.
They just think like, oh, you must have this
like crazy configuration that gets you data.
Sure, I'll give you the same data, but are
you gonna be able to find the same bugs?
Yeah, yeah, it's very, very common.
I think it also kind of, the reason for this,
and I also had this very feeling before I
started hunting that to find a bug, I need
to find a subdomain or a target that nobody
else finds.
And I think the reason for this, the reason
beginners ask this question too much is that
they are not confident enough that they can
find a bug in a target that anybody else has
hacked.
And we just see over and over and over again
that everyone skips bugs because we just see
in the recent live hacking events, you said
it was a target, live hacking events, for
those who didn't know are, actually, maybe
you can tell people what are live hacking
events, you know better than me.
So the live hacking events are, HackerOne
has been doing this for years, I think other
companies do them now too, but HackerOne is
like live hacking events in a city.
They pick a random city, this last one was
in London.
They usually pick one target, sometimes two
or three, depending on the event.
But usually it's like one or two companies,
they fly everybody in, they put us in a room,
we hack.
The cool thing about the bug bounty events
with the live hacking events is you have direct
access to the triage team, you have direct
access to the engineering team.
If I have to make an assumption, I could go
up to an engineer and validate that assumption
or show him a possible route or whatever that
is, you have access to them.
This last one is public knowledge, it was
Zoom and Salesforce.
Both of them were on the local HackerOne chair,
so we can confidently talk about Zoom and
Salesforce being the targets, which these
are multi-billion dollar company maybe at
this point in revenue, but also the security
teams they have are huge.
Chances are people have hacked on Zoom a bunch
of times or Zoom has done a bunch of pen tests,
there's one of the most commonly used tools
out there.
But people still found a ton of vulnerability
because not only they have new things that
are coming out, they're developing new features,
they give us access to and so on, but it's
just the fact that people have their pressure,
you have to find bugs, this is the target,
this is what it is, you have to look for bugs
in them.
The comment that you made about the assumption
of finding a subdomain to be first to find
a vulnerability in, that assumption works.
There's a payout in finding a subdomain, being
the first to find it in a company like Uber,
Yahoo, big large organizations that are public.
It helps when you're first to find a subdomain,
because if they deploy something for testing
purposes and you're the first to find it as
it goes up, then you're probably going to
be the first to find a vulnerability, but
that's not the only way to find a vulnerability
and these life hacking events are for sure
a good example of showing that.
Yeah, and speaking of life hacking events,
we have a question from Johan Carson from
Twitter.
How do you create teams for life hacking events?
I think the life hacking events, the teams
that are already created is just based on
everyone that's already been friends.
A lot of the same people keep on collaborating
over and over and over again.
I don't usually have a team, unfortunately,
or fortunately for me.
I try to team up with people, but I think
it's mostly I end up hacking with people that
I'm close with most of the time.
And if they're not there or if that's not
the case, just you bump shoulders with people.
So in my last video when I talked about Zoom,
I worked with Alex Chapman and Shmuel.
I've known Alex for years, great guy, but
Shmuel I had never met in my life ever.
I never even knew who he was.
We've never talked at all online.
And we're in the lobby waiting for the car
to take us to the event.
He walks up to me and goes, hey, I'm Shmuel,
what's your name?
And I'm like, oh, hey, I'm Ben.
You know, I'm the homestick on the platform.
Oh yeah, I've seen your blah, blah, blah.
And what are you doing here?
And then I tell him like, oh yeah, I've got
this bug, but I can't figure it out.
He goes, oh, we can for sure do this one thing
to it.
And I'm like, no way.
And then 16 hours later, I'm sitting here,
I'm high-fiving him a million times.
Like, yeah, yeah, we did it, we did it.
16 hours later, right?
It's just, it's a cool thing to be at these
events because just bumping to someone in
the lobby or at the event where you can just
go, hey, I'm so-and-so, what's up?
Just easier and more natural if you have that
to go walk up to people.
It makes it just easier to collaborate.
And, you know, honestly, teams aren't the
only way.
I know people that just collaborate with anybody
and there's a collab channel that you can
work with.
So do you mostly team up with either your
friends or someone you bump up at the event
for like the whole event you collaborate together?
Or is it more like with, in this case, to
exploit a bug that you found?
I think, so I've only been to a couple of
it.
So I used to work at HackerOne and I used
to go to the events as an employee so I couldn't
participate a lot of times.
This is my third or fourth event.
The first one I went to, I think, was Vegas
last year.
No, Denver last year.
That one, I think, Justin and I, Renovator,
we were just like, hey, let's team up for
this event together and hack.
We teamed up, made some money and that was
it.
But we didn't find a whole lot of stuff.
It was kind of like defeated the purpose,
but it was an experience I wanted to do together,
right?
And then the second event was Vegas.
I work with Ziad a lot.
He's one of my good friends.
Him and I were just, we haven't seen each
other for years.
Hey, let's team up.
We get there and neither one of us had bugs.
The night before the event, we set up all
night hacking and we ended up finding a ton
of bug.
That kind of worked out.
It wasn't like we agreed to be a team, but
it was just like, we're friends.
I would rather work with him than anybody
else because I trust the guy, I know him.
It just makes it more fun.
And then in LA, I went and did solo.
They didn't find anything.
It was way over my head.
And then this event, I went in solo, but I
collaborated with people like Eric.
I collaborated with, what's his name?
I just mentioned Shmuel and Alex Chapman.
And it was just more of a, I found someone
that has interests like I do or knows the
things that I do or thinks we can do something
together.
Screw it, let's team up and let's see where
it goes.
And the other question from Johan was, so
when you're collaborating together, do you
split all the bounties that you find?
Or there are sometimes cases where, yes, you
are somewhat hunting together, but one person
exploited the bug from the very beginning
to the very end on their own.
Depends.
I know some teams that do split, event splits.
So when you go, hey, let's team up.
I know people that go, hey, let's team up
for this whole event.
Everything we make, we split it three ways.
I know people that do that or four ways, whatever
that is.
For me personally, I just split whatever I
find with somebody.
So in that case, for my best desktop bug that
I got with Shmuel and Alex Chapman, they were
just like both, we don't care how much, just
give us what's fair.
Ali was also involved and I gotta give him
a shout out too.
So we split it in a different way because
it was what people did.
The three of us did something and then Ali
did something different.
We split them differently.
Each of us got different splits based on what
we did.
For my other bug that I did, I actually worked
with Today's New Eric and it was a four-step
vulnerability.
And one of the steps kind of had a blocker
on what we could achieve.
And if it wasn't for him, we couldn't fully
show the impact.
The bug was there, but the impact would have
been a lot higher.
But because it was like one of the four or
five steps, we split in a smaller percentage.
It was me, somebody else, and him.
We did a smaller percentage and he was okay
with it because we needed five different steps.
People are very fair, I think.
As long as you're not just telling him, I'm
not paying you or like, oh, I don't think,
I want to give you only 10%.
It's just, it's really, everyone's super friendly.
Everyone's there to have a good time and then
people want to offer you to make money.
But I just don't think anyone's ever been
like, you know, I'm not going to pay this
person or anything like that.
It's just, you all make these agreements in
the beginning, you can be upfront with it
or you can say, hey, we'll figure it out at
the end and then you just go back and forth.
But I've never seen anybody, you know, have
issues with splits or payouts like that.
Do you have any tips for people so they can
also avoid any problems when collaborating
with others?
I would say set a collaboration agreement
in the beginning if you don't know the person
or you've never worked with them or whatever
the reasoning be.
I usually like to do the 50-50 split when
I'm, you know, hey, I just got this target
or we're both on the same target, you want
to hack together on this thing and we'll do
a 50-50 split.
But the life-hacking agreements are just different
because you have your team and then the other
person has something else, you know, you just
want to, you need that one thing from this
other person and just make deals, I think.
But in general, it's just, I think I value
friendship more than money.
So if you can make a friendship out of this
thing, a long life friend, for example, for
your entire life, that's worth more.
Zion is a prime example for me.
Him and I, every time we used to do bounties
together, I think you actually covered one
of our findings way earlier in your channel.
Yeah, yeah, from Airbnb.
It was like a six or seven step bug.
Yeah, so like something like that, you know,
when we were doing Airbnb, he killed that
vulnerability, a lot of it was him, we still
split it.
And then I would make up for it by finding,
you know, three, four, five eye doors while
he was not even like online or while we're
working together.
It was just, but we created a friendship through
that.
You know, I've known him for like, you know,
I want to say nine to 10 years now.
It was just like, hey, you want to hack on
this thing?
Yeah, let's do it.
And then the assumption was 50-50.
And then in the recent years where we don't
hack as much, we've all grown up with other
stuff now, right?
We still try and go back to that, but it's
just different now.
But I just think you can make a friend that
you guys could make way more money together
than that one time you hack with each other
and you make like an extra $2,000, who cares?
Like you can make extra $40,000 in a year
together if you become friends.
Yeah, yeah, that's a really, really nice deep,
deep for people that relationships are much
more valuable than money is.
Yeah, you don't, this industry is very small.
This community is very small.
The industry is very small.
You never know where you're going to end up.
So make friends, network yourself.
I'm not saying don't make money, but money
could go, you know, you can make, your money
could go a long way when you have the right
people in the right network.
Yeah.
And go spend some of your money.
I give this advice to somebody.
Go spend some of the money you make.
Don't, you know, save up money, invest it,
but also go enjoy life with some of the money
you make.
Yeah, that's a super, super nice tip.
We'll also jump to this in a second, but let's
stick to hacking.
How do you choose your programs these days?
Now it's more on the research and the things.
Like if I wanted some sort of a research,
that's a big part of it.
Like what companies can I hack on for this
research based on, you know, the applications
they have or the stack they have.
Um, the company name is a big one.
You know, Red Bull was a good example.
It was just, I don't drink Red Bull, even
though they send me cases of it.
I don't really drink Red Bull, but it was
just like, I have always wanted to hack Red
Bull and see what it's like, because they're
so involved in like sponsorships and events.
Uh, that's a good one.
Um, I don't know what the other programs it's,
if I'm doing it for a bounty aspect to make
a little bit of money, then the bounty amount
is a big, you know, part of that I look at.
I don't look for like a program that's like
medium pay.
Out to like $5,000.
No, but I don't want to do a program that's
like medium pay out.
It's like 50 bucks or a hundred bucks because
there's so many other programs that I can
hack on.
So I just look at like, if I find them, most
of them, I want to say nine or 10 times that
I find a vulnerability.
To me, it's a medium because I'm not open,
you know, I'm not, you know, sending with
open redirects and theoretical bugs, right?
I'm sending in at least cross-site scriptings.
Uh, I'm sending eye doors, authorization issues,
SSRF.
So it's like medium and higher, right?
So a medium, if it pays me $500, I'm okay
with that because if I spend five hours and
I find a medium bug, that's still about $100
an hour.
It's not, you know, what I would make on an
average for a compendium test maybe, but it's
still better than any other daytime job.
Yeah.
And it's just like the minimum and then you
find a big payout and it's like crashes this
average.
And also like, I'm, I'm, I'm huge on momentum.
I don't care if people believe in momentum.
I'm a big, I've drank the cool out of momentum.
I think you need to build momentum to find
more bugs.
So if I find a bug today on this program,
it's a medium, I go, huh, I wonder if there's
more that I find three more mediums.
I go, okay, I wonder if I could get a high
now.
I wonder if I could do this thing.
And then more and more of these mediums you
find, the more you understand the application,
then you find a high.
And then you, you know, you realize, oh shoot,
there's all these different things that I
didn't look for.
But it's just momentum is a big thing because
it helps you go, okay, well I spent 10 hours.
At least I found the bug.
So at that point you go, I don't even care
how much it is.
At least I know I found it.
Right?
I've spent 10 hours.
At least I know there's a vulnerability here.
And my gut feeling was right.
Yeah.
So do you not have a feeling, because for
me, when I start a new program and I report
the first bug, I sometimes have like, I want
to wait for how they handle the bug before
I hunt there more.
And from what you said, it seems like you
don't have this.
I mean, this is where I would look at it.
If you send that bug in, right?
If they pay you for it, great, right?
The program is going to go back to it, right?
But what if between then and the two days
that they took him, a week that they took
him to handle it and report it and pay you,
you could have found 10 more bugs that somebody
else found and reported.
Yeah.
Right?
Often it's like longer than a week.
Yeah, but you know what I mean though?
It's like when you send the report, you've
already started looking at this program.
You already invested time, three, four hours
to find a bug.
And if you know there's more bugs, why not
just simply report them?
Worst case is you don't make money and it
sucks.
Trust me, I get it.
It's not ideal.
You shouldn't work for free.
But I would rather miss out on my 12, 14 hours
that I did than miss out on like the 10K that
I could have made by just looking for more
bugs.
And I already got momentum.
Worst case is I don't fix it.
I want to redact the crap out of these reports
and put it in my next talk if it's something
interesting I could talk about.
Yeah, that's 100% makes sense.
I think I would try to go with this momentum
because I think it can really help.
There are some programs I do what you say
though.
Like don't get me wrong.
There are times when I'm like, these numbers
don't look good on this program.
Like average time to pay out is like three
months.
You know, I do that.
But when it's a brand new program or if it's
a program that looks okay, people are hacking
on it, top hackers are hacking on it.
I just, the question becomes like, is it worth
missing out on bugs that you may be finding?
You know, you're going to miss out on $5,000
in two days of hacking because you're not
sure versus what are you going to lose is
two days of work.
But at least if you're enjoying hacking, that
two days doesn't matter.
You enjoy doing what you were doing, right?
Yeah, that's true.
It makes complete sense.
With so many years of experience, how do you
still learn new stuff today?
I think my learning is a little bit different
because I have to teach people.
So I learned things mostly, how do I learn
these things to explain it to people?
That's one of the ways that I make it my objective.
I think learning nowadays isn't really a hard
thing to do.
You have all these platforms like your Hack
the Box, your TryHackMe, Hacker101, Pentester
Lab.
What am I missing?
I know there's a bunch that I'm missing.
There's so many of them, right?
WebSecAcademy.
Oh yeah, that's really cool.
WebSecAcademy, Pico CTF, or all these random
CTFs that happen, right?
You have so many things you can learn from
that there is literally zero shortage of knowledge.
When I first started doing bug bounties, none
of these existed.
TryHackMe was founded in 2018, I want to say.
Hack the Box was founded in 2017.
Pentester Lab, I think, was 2015, maybe 2016.
None of these were around, and you don't have
people sharing research like they do nowadays.
Read it right up.
Go on Twitter.
Do a CTF, recreate the challenge, or if you
can't recreate it, recreate the POC by looking
for that same vulnerability if you can.
I think there's a lot of different ways to
learn.
Conferences, Twitch streams, there's all these
different ways, but I think the best way to
learn is to just go and do these things simply,
to be honest.
Yeah, yeah, I agree.
What areas of hacking other than web are you
good at?
I think API kind of is different, but it's
kind of web.
It's just really fuzzing in API.
I think it's sometimes fun to do.
I really enjoyed, because of Zoom, I really
got into desktop hacking, and I want to explore
that more and more.
I think there is so much cool stuff you can
do with a desktop app that I want to get into
more.
I've gotten a little bit better at mobile
hacking thanks to HackerOne's live hacking
events, because it forced me to create a setup
on my laptop to actually know how to do a
SSO cert pinning, and all that stuff has become
easier.
I enjoy it, but it's just the setup is so
much work, I feel like sometimes.
Yeah, it is.
But it is a good place to find some interesting
bugs.
What else?
I think those are honestly it.
I think web hacking's gonna always be the
fun thing to do, but doing some recon sometimes.
I think I really enjoy, from a recon perspective,
not for just bug bounties, but just for hacking,
I really enjoy learning about a company's
infrastructure, how they name things, where
things are, how they mess up when you can
open up a website by IP and not the host name,
just those little things that make me go,
ah, I'm smarter than you.
I don't mean that I'm really smarter than
them, but you just feel good.
You go, ah, I didn't think that would work,
or, ah, I found this application.
This is how you access it.
I really enjoy those things, even though they
don't always translate into bounties, but
it's just a fun little thing of going, oh,
I see this GitLab instance.
You know, like, well, I see this GI instance.
I wonder if any information comes out of it.
I like those things, but yeah, there isn't
like a, I think web's gonna always be one
of my favorite things to do.
There was specifically a question about web3.
Oh, no.
I'm not a web3 expert by any means.
I just made a lot of web3 content, thanks
to Halborn.
I was exposed to a lot of web3 things, but
it's way over my head, but honestly, if you
have, I think I know what the question is.
I can guess what it is.
Let me see if I can answer without you asking,
but honestly, if you have an interest in developing
and you have a good understanding of programming
languages and you're okay with learning and
doing source code review, web3 is very fun
and very lucrative.
You can make a lot of money.
If you're looking into getting started with
web3, which I think is probably the question,
honestly, the easiest way I can- There's actually
no follow-up question to this.
Oh, okay.
Well, I was going to say, if people want to
get into web3, I get a lot of questions because
of the content that I made with Halborn.
If you want to get into web3, honestly, Zillow
has some really good resources.
I know Halborn themselves have a lot of good
resources, and I think they have a CTF on
their GitHub and they have a Zion, which is
pretty, really dope.
Now, you have all the tools you need for it
that I recommend people using, but outside
of that, the biggest thing is just, it's like
anything else.
It's like doing it.
You have to be okay with sitting in, sitting
down and just reviewing source code and having
analogies and hunches that you're going to
go on and testing them out.
Resource-wise, I don't have a lot of resources.
Go watch my videos that I've created.
HackerMate is a really good hacker out of,
I want to say Spain or Portugal.
I think he's in Spain.
He has some really good content.
I would say follow him as well.
Farron is really good.
I follow him on Twitter.
He has some good resources.
But I know a lot of the Web3 stuff with Immunify
also as well.
I have good resources and it's a lot of source
code review.
Yeah, okay.
Let's skip to the content creation side of
things.
Recently, there has been a tweet saying that
top bug bounty hunters don't share their methodologies.
You are a top bug bounty hunter and you share
a lot of methodologies in your videos since
years.
So what's your opinion about that tweet?
I think people want to have handouts.
You can't say people aren't sharing because
if people weren't sharing, then how did nuclear
templates exist?
Why would they have thousands of nuclear templates?
If people didn't share, why is there so...
Why does NahumCon exist if people didn't share?
Right?
You see all these top hackers, RhinoRaider,
Shubbz, ZLZ, all these different people that
come from NahumCon and speak to Jason Haddix.
If those didn't exist, then what are people
talking about?
There's a difference between people sharing
their knowledge and people sharing outright
how they make their money.
You don't see Apple putting all their blueprints
of their devices online.
They tell you how they do marketing.
They show you what they're doing or they show
you what the device does.
But I think there's a difference between handouts
and making money.
I think the bug bounty community is one of
the most toxic communities out there in some
senses, but people are very welcoming and
people are quick to share.
If you're not a dick and if you're nice to
people and you aren't begging for things,
people are quick to help you out.
And I'm one of the people that was on that
side of it for a very long time of asking
people for help.
If you go to my tweets from back in the day,
you will see me asking, what's a host letter
injection?
What's a parameter pollution?
Is there anything that I didn't understand
back then?
And people were messaging me in DMs or replying
to me and responding.
And that was in 2014.
Yeah, but the key is asking a good question
as well.
Because a lot of people are just asking either
a very generic question, which suggests they
invested no time into before asking the question.
And then there's just no answer.
For me as well, I also get a lot of messages.
I don't respond to a lot of messages because
they are like, hi, Greg, how are you doing?
Or very generic, how do you start?
Blah, blah, blah, things like this.
But when I see that someone invested some
time before writing to me, I would just feel
bad not replying to them.
And I know, again, from being on the other
side that other people help as well.
So I think there's a couple of things.
I get the same.
I get a lot of questions from people coming
in.
And it's easy to tell who's trying and who's
not trying.
I get that people want to say, hey, how are
you doing as a first message because you don't
want to outright just ask someone for a favor,
right?
I get that.
But you can say, hey, how are you doing?
But you want something.
You're not just messaging me to just ask me
how I'm doing.
So learn how to ask a question.
My rule of thumb for everybody that's watching
this is if you want to ask a question from
anybody, hey, how are you doing?
Or hey, hello, how's it going?
Whatever you want to say, greet them, obviously.
And then say, hey, I'm working on X.
I'm struggling with Y.
I've tried these things.
I was wondering if you know anything about
this thing or how I could proceed.
I've had a lot of cases of people just saying,
hey, how do you export XSS?
Go look at Website Academy.
I'm happy to help you, but it's just I can't
help everybody like that, right?
And I've had some really cool ones on Discord
that people have messaged me like, hey, I
have this SSRF on this thing.
I've tried these things.
Can you help me?
Or they go, I have an SSRF I can't export.
I go, OK, I want to see the SSRF.
So I ask them, what have you tried?
But when they tell me what they have tried,
I go, oh, I know what to exactly answer for
you.
It makes my life easier when I have other
people that are asking me for the same thing.
So learning how to ask a question is one thing,
but also people just look at the preview of
your message.
When the message just says, hey, I'm going
to think you're a bot, because there's a lot
of bots on Twitter, right?
So stand out with your question.
Hey, I'm working on X.
I was wondering why.
And I'm curious to see how many people are
going to do this now after watching this episode.
Yeah, true.
What is your motivation for creating content?
I think like when I was doing Bark Brownies
back in 2013, in 2014, there wasn't a lot
of resources.
There wasn't anybody sharing any of their
experience.
I wish somebody was there to do these things.
And I think it's something that I wish I had.
And I want to be that person for a lot of
people.
And I want, honestly, I think hacking changed
my life in a really drastic way.
In a very huge way.
Then I think a lot of, if I did it, more people
can definitely do it too.
Okay, and how do you now organize your time
between all the different projects and hacking
that you do?
I think it's just mostly, I used to do like
blogs.
I would do like this hour, I'm going to do
content.
This hour, I'm going to hack.
Then I realized that context switching doesn't
help, especially when you do something creative.
So now I have days about my content, I have
days that are my hacking days.
I have days that are like my more chill days.
It's my days that I make thumbnails or whatever
else.
It's just I'm making them today.
So like Monday and Tuesdays, I used to, Sunday,
Monday, Tuesdays, I used to stream.
Right now I have those open.
So right now my Mondays are like my content
creation, my weekly planning.
Tuesdays, I do some light hacking.
And if I have Pentest, I do a lot of my Pentest,
Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursdays.
And then Fridays is more of a content again.
And then Saturdays are like my, I'm going
to catch up on whatever I didn't get to do.
And then when I stream on Sundays, my only
rule, I don't work on Sundays other than my
stream and my thumbnails for the next day.
But other than that, I don't work on Sundays
at all.
It's just the one day that I give myself to
do whatever I need.
Okay.
And what are some other activities that help
you just relax and chill out?
I play a lot of Call of Duty Warzone.
I don't know if that gives me the ability
to chill out because it stresses me out when
I play the game.
My buddy's like doing a dopamine detox.
Like I'm not playing Call of Duty because
it gives me dopamine.
I'm like, it gives you dopamine?
It makes me stress, it gives me anxiety.
But video games in general, it's a good one.
I watch a lot of like TV shows.
Sometimes I go on these binge watches.
I'm going in the process of like re-watching
some of my favorite TV shows.
And I'm like, oh, I'm going to binge watch
this.
I'm going to binge watch this.
I'm going to binge watch one of my favorite
TV shows.
So I'm like, right now I'm watching Limitless.
I just finished another show.
I don't know what it was, but I'm just re-watching
some of my favorite shows.
I'm going to re-watch Suits soon again.
I love that show.
Yeah, so just watch those, and then traveling
has been a good one.
I tell people to spend their money.
But for that reason, like go and travel and
go and do some things to remind yourself why
you work so hard.
Yeah.
That's a big one.
What are your favorite travel destinations?
I think, so I want to go to like Eastern Asia.
I've never, I've only been to Singapore and
on the Asian side of the world.
I really want to go to Japan and I want to
go to Thailand that I haven't been.
But out of all the places I have been so far,
I'm always going to love Switzerland and some
areas of France, some areas of France.
I'm going to make that a very clear thing.
But Europe has been a fun one.
I've seen a lot of European countries.
I'm excited to go to Hungary soon.
I've seen, I want to go to Romania at some
point if I can.
But favorite ones that I've ever seen, I want
to say Portugal was fun.
I love going to Amsterdam once in a while.
It's a really fun one.
And Italy was also a little fun.
I'm not going to lie.
I had a blast in Italy.
Yeah, there's a lot.
There's a lot of countries you've been to.
I've seen a lot of, this year alone, I think
I've done nine or 10 countries with work.
Okay.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's great.
Do you do like holidays without work or is
it more like workation type?
So I'm taking my first ever holiday in August.
Like I'm probably going on a holiday in like
years since COVID at least.
Because COVID was like, there's no holidays,
right?
Most of the time I have my laptop on me, even
when I went.
So I'm Iranian.
Iranian New Year's in March.
When I went out there to see my family, I
worked out of the two weeks I was there, I
worked like eight of them, nine of them at
least.
And it wasn't like eight or nine days back
to back.
It was like four days here, two days there,
one day there.
You know, it was like, there was no span of
like having time off.
So in August, I've told myself August 20th,
19th for a week, I don't care.
Everything, unless it's going to burn, I'm
not going to touch it.
So I'm going to have content ready to come
out, but I'm not going to be working at all.
It's going to be a purification after all
the mad and craziness of DEF CON.
Yeah, yeah.
Congratulations on making this decision and
definitely will help you out later.
I hope so, man.
I hope so.
When you create content, do you outsource
a lot of your work?
I've had my videographer, Clay, that I work
with for I think three years now.
Yeah, for three years.
He does a lot of my edits.
I'm not really good at editing videos.
But also it just takes stress off of my plate.
That's one.
With NowHomeCon, I have my best friend who's
helping me with some of the logistics of it,
just because it's a lot of work and it's not,
you know, you need more help than one person
to organize a conference.
Yeah, I've learned to ask for help.
I have people that help me with some stuff,
but there are some things that I genuinely
enjoy doing right now.
Like thumbnails is a big one.
I love making my own thumbnails right now,
but I would love to outsource it at some point.
I don't know if you saw, literally today YouTube
released for a public beta A-B testing on
YouTube directly.
But it's probably, it's only for a limited
group of creators.
I don't have it.
I think we have to be one of those, like at
least verified.
I'm not verified yet either.
So I think it's one of those, like you have
to be verified to get access to it.
Yeah, we'll see about it.
It will be great.
Yeah.
And also we use Twitter a lot apart from the
YouTube.
And recently there has been an alternative
growing from Meta, Red's app.
In Europe, I didn't experience this yet.
I'm waiting for them to get the registration
and all this stuff out of the way.
What's your experience with the app so far?
Honestly, dude, I'm going to get a lot of
hate for this because Zuckerberg is behind
this one.
But I love threads.
I'm not as active as I was in the early days,
but I just don't have a lot of time to be
on social media.
But honestly, I think it gives me hope.
I don't have a problem with Twitter.
I just think they've made it pay to play,
like you have to pay to be engaged.
And like I even tried to do the verification
thing, but I just think the engagement on
Twitter has dropped drastically.
I don't know if people just left Twitter or
because I don't post enough, but threads gives
me more engagement.
And I think threads is a good place for your
community versus Twitter is for the community
you're a part of, if that makes sense.
So threads is my friends and my fans and my
followers.
Twitter is them, but also the InfoSec broader
community as well.
Yeah.
Yeah, and it'll take years to recreate what
we have on Twitter on the other platform,
but we'll see.
Yeah, I think there is hopes for it for sure.
I think hopefully more and more comes out
of this thing and we'll see how it goes.
I'm hopeful that...
I think having a number of platforms is good
to have something like that.
It just sucks that...
I get that it sucks that it's meta again.
I get that part.
But at the end of the day, I think having
more people have platforms like this is very
helpful, man.
Yeah, and you have quite a bit of a head start
because you have a big following on Instagram,
no?
Let me see.
I think I have like 25,000.
I have 25,000 and some change on there.
Yeah, it gives you a head start, but I think
the thing with my Instagram is I have a lot
of personal friends on there too.
So it may take a while before I get a good
following there, but it's like any other community,
man.
It gives you access to...
It's giving me access to new people that I
don't even knew existed.
Even on my Instagram that I've never seen
them.
I see them more and more on there now.
So I would tell anybody that wants to get
in a community that just gives you another
group of people that we never would have reached
if it wasn't for events or whatever app you're
on.
Okay, the last question.
Earlier, you told me how you saw the bug bounty
industry change over the last years.
So now give me your prediction of what will
happen in the industry in the next five years.
I think more and more companies are going
to do bug bounties, honestly.
I don't have a big prediction of this is what's
going to happen in the next couple of years.
I just think there's going to be more companies
that are huge that don't have a bug bounty
program that are going to come around more.
I think it's going to become more normal.
And I have a feeling, something that we're
moving forward to, is that I think more governments
are going to require government agencies and
large corporations that handle a lot of private
information or IPIs at least, to have some
sort of a VDP and a channel for people to
get involved with.
So I think at the end of it, it's going to
be just more of the same thing.
It's just going to have a huge growth, I think.
So it'll be interesting to see where it goes
and what other parts of the industry we're
going to come out through.
Because I know some of these bug bounty platforms
are doing ASM now or have been doing ASM.
I know Pentas is becoming a thing.
Maybe we make red teaming into the next thing.
Like we have an actual red team of people
that are doing things on these platforms.
That's not just web.
They could do social engineering at some point
and things like that.
Yeah, that would be crazy.
That sounds nice.
Yeah.
Thank you so much for joining me today.
It was a goldmine of tips.
So now when I ask you, when should people
follow you, do you say Twitter or do you say
threads?
I say on all social media platforms is at
NahamSec.
And if they're watching this video of yours,
please go ahead and like and subscribe to
this man.
I don't know where you're going to put him.
This guy, whatever he is on the channel.
Like and subscribe.
Support your content creators that are making
free content for you guys that helps you navigate
your career or get your first bug or whatever
it is that your goals are.
Support him.
That's the easiest thing you can do is just
like this right here, drop a comment and go
to his channel and subscribe.
It's the biggest thing you can do to help
content creators.
Yeah, guys, you just have to do what Ben said.
Take my word for it.
Thanks for joining me today.
Of course, man.
Thanks for having me.
Bye.
Incredible how much we all can learn from
this interview.
But if you are still hungry for more, first,
make sure you are subscribed to NahamSec on
YouTube because he's regularly producing great
videos.
And if you want to check out one of them,
I suggest you this one titled How to do bug
bounty in 2023.
For now, thank you for listening and goodbye.